《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously, on "Arrow"...
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译   蜜色阳光  Michael  SophiaSaaaga
帕尔默博士实现了微型技术
Dr. Palmer got miniaturization to work.
开始
Do it!
翻译     Reginamoon  小酸奶  Silence
我没死
I'm not dead.
联邦现金存款
校对   Michale  苹果果 精校   陈小圈
时间轴风吹来的那片云  特效  咖啡Lee
后期   咖啡Lee    总监   苹果果
我是237号小组  我们在星城银行
This is Field Crew 237, we're at the Star City Bank.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
我们遭到袭击了  需要紧急援助
We're under attack! Immediate assistance!
那些幽灵  他们准备抢劫运钞车了
The ghosts, they're about to take over the armored cars.
是啊  就像以前一样
Yeah, it's just like old times.
后面还有保安
There are guards in the back.
我们会救出他们的  快走
We'll get 'em. Go!
他们把所有的钱都烧了
They burned all the money.
他们不需要这些钱
They didn't need it.
联邦政府运这些钱来资助星城银行
Federal government sent this to prop up Star City Bank.
蜂巢只是想确保这些钱无法送到
Hive just wanted to make sure that didn't happen.
绿 箭
第四季  第七集
我听说过有的人钱多得花不完
I've heard of having money to burn,
但抢了钱拿去烧  真是新鲜事
but stealing money to burn, that's new.
达克没开玩笑
Darhk's not kidding--
他真的想让这个城市灭亡
he really wants this city to die.
对  但为什么
Yeah, but why?
这样对蜂巢有什么好处
I mean, what does HIVE have to gain from any of this?
行动基地
A base of operations.
他们总得找一个能指挥行动的地方
They have to be able to operate out of somewhere.
有什么地方比一座死城更好呢
What better spot than a dead city?
还有个基本上不管事的警局
With almost a dead police department.
我们拿下的蜂巢成员的牙齿
Any luck from that tooth
有没有什么新发现
we got off the HIVE member that we took down?
只知道DNA标记的破坏
Only that the deterioration of the DNA markers
绝对是非自然原因
was most definitely not natural.
这是由什么引起的
Which means it was caused by what?
我和柯蒂斯这一个月都在找寻原因
Curtis and I have been trying to figure that out for the past month.
也许雷能找到答案
Maybe Ray will have better luck.
我会问他的
I will ask.
你有时间吗
Hey, you got a sec?
有
Yeah.
绝密文件
调查报告
你从哪里拿到这些的
Where'd you get this?
兰斯给我的
I got that from Lance.
达米恩·达克给他的
Who got it from Damian Darhk.
-约翰  这...  -这是能证明
- John, this... ? - Is pretty definitive evidence
蜂巢杀了安迪是因为
that HIVE had andy killed
他们两方的犯罪行为有利益冲突的确凿证据
because his criminal operations conflicted with theirs.
这跟你告诉我关于安迪的事情毫不相符
That doesn't track at all with what you have told me about Andy.
奥利弗  这跟我认识的安迪不相符
Oliver, that doesn't track with what I knew about Andy.
但是...
But...
我想我真的一点都不了解他
I guess I really never knew him at all.
一定有原因的
There's got to be some explanation.
也许他是卧底
Maybe he was undercover.
哥们  听着  证据都在这了
Hey, man, listen, it's all right there.
-事实就是事实  -我想说的是
- The facts are the facts. - All I'm saying,
安迪是你哥哥
Andy was your brother,
我们应该假设他是清白的
and he deserves the benefit of the doubt.
相信我
Trust me.
有时候事情并不像表面上看的那样
Things aren't always what they seem.
好吧  好吧
Yeah, yeah.
瑞特会不高兴的
Reiter's not going to like this.
非常不高兴
Not one bit.
瓦勒德是个能手
Vlad was a good worker,
而且他有号召力
and they listened to him.
我别无选择
Well, I didn't have a choice.
他当时要杀了我
He was going to kill me.
听上去不像是他会做的事
Doesn't sound like something he'd do.
也许...  也许他也别无选择
Maybe... maybe he didn't have a choice, either.
也许有人指使他那么做
Maybe someone put him up to it.
也许是报仇
Maybe it was revenge.
报什么仇
Revenge for what?
为泰安娜报仇
For Taiana.
那个偷了毒品后  被你杀死的贱人
That drug stealing bitch you choked out?
瓦勒德是她哥哥
Vlad was her brother.
谢谢你这么快就赶来
Thank you for coming by on such short notice.
我很高兴能有事做
Well, happy to have something to do.
说实话  我对新找回的自由
To be honest, I'm feeling at a bit of a loss
有点不知所措
of what to do with my newfound freedom.
还有身高
And height.
所有东西本来就那么大吗
Is everything always this big?
如果你在找事情做
If you're looking for something to do,
为什么不
why not try, I don't know,
告诉大家你还活着
declare yourself undead,
然后想办法把公司的管理权要回来呢
try getting your company back.
你之前说有事要找我帮忙
You said you had something that you needed help on?
别转移话题
Don't change the subject.
我没有
I'm not!
我是一个没死的亿万富翁总裁
I am a recently undead billionaire CEO.
我的时间很宝贵
My time is at a premium.
我能帮你做什么
What can I do for you?
谢谢  我之前还在想我的牙齿去哪了
Thanks, I was wondering where my tooth went.
这是约翰从一个幽灵嘴里拔出来的
John pulled this off of a ghost.
里面的氰化物是为自杀准备的
It's their cyanide retirement plan.
我们想从中提取DNA信息  但是...
We tried pulling DNA off of it, but...
但一半的基因标记都不见了  这不可能
But half of the genetic markers are missing. That's impossible.
你是说像
You mean like,
"一个人能缩小到薯条那么小"一样不可能
"a guy who can shrink to the size of a french fry" impossible?
你有什么装备吗  我对层析法不太熟悉
Well, do you have any equipment? I'm fresh out of chromatographs.
有这个
Got that.
说回你为什么不想回帕尔默科技的话题吧
Can we circle back to why you won't come back to Palmer Tech?
你的回归绝对是我们股价所需要的动力
Your return is exactly what our stock price needs.
真是不可思议
It's incredible.
基因序列被选择性地分解了
The genetic code has been selectively degraded.
我们知道  我们觉得DNA标记这么混乱
We know. We think it's to scramble the DNA markers
是为了防止被确认出身份  但怎么做到的
so they can't be IDed. But how?
看起来是用了一种人造化合物
Well, it looks like it was done with a synthetic compound.
就好像化学生物基因改造
Like a chemical CRISPR/Cas9.
「细菌和古细菌在长期演化过程中
形成的一种适应性免疫防御」
三氧化二砷
Lastrapium trioxide.
沃夫曼
生物制剂公司
沃夫曼生物制剂公司对此有专利
Wolfman Biologics has a patent on it.
谢谢
Thank you.
明天晚上
OK, tomorrow night,
警署慈善组织晚会
Patrolman's Benevolent Association Gala.
正装出席  所以你需要一身礼服
It's black tie, so you need a tux.
哪一套  他差不多有五十套
Which one? He's got like 50.
以前是的  可现在我没有了
Maybe back in the day. I don't have a tux.
租一套  这无所谓
Get a rental. Doesn't really matter.
星城的历届市长都会参加警署慈善晚会
Every mayor in the history of Star City has attended the PBA.
我在主席台的领导座位旁边给你留了位置
I secured a spot for you on the dais with the brass,
但我们要确保你的演讲能切中要点
but we need to make sure that your keynote is on point.
也就是说我们需要表明
Which means, we need to find a way to say that
我们会帮助警察并且
the police need our help without...
-不会为了自己的利益而背叛他们  -对
- Throwing them under the bus. - Right.
我以为你公民课挂科了
I thought you failed civics class.
只是D减而已  谢谢提起
A D-minus, thank you.
艾利克斯让这变得有趣起来
Alex has a way of making this interesting.
马尔科姆来电
不好意思  打错了
Sorry, wrong number.
我们说到哪了
What were we saying?
下面是奥利弗的竞选纲领
Moving on to Oliver's platform.
我收到你关于清理星城湾的邮件了
I got your email about cleaning up Star City Bay.
没错
Yes!
就星城的现况来看
You know, with everything this city's facing right now,
像这样嬉皮式的琐碎项目...
a hippie, crunchy program like--
这个嬉皮式的琐碎项目会增加几百个工作岗位
A hippie, crunchy program that will add hundreds of jobs,
改善周围居民环境
help gentrify the surrounding neighborhoods,
鼓励外部投资
and encourage outside investment.
还会让投票者们犯困
And put voters to sleep.
我们需要关注犯罪和就业
We need to focus on crime and jobs.
这个项目就能做到
Which this program will address.
费利西蒂来电
我明天会发新闻稿
Hey, I will put out a press release tomorrow.
-我要接这个电话  -好
- I got to take this. - OK.
我觉得你哥哥发现我们了
I think your brother's onto us.
没有  没有  而且就算他发现了
No. No, and even if he was,
他也不是我老板
it's not like he's the boss of me.
对  可他是我老板
No, he's the boss of me.
-我知道  -还好你哥哥不是个杀手
- I know.  - I'm just glad your brother's not a killer.
快手
Speedy!
Speedy...
西娅  抱歉  那是她的昵称  我们得走了
Thea. Sorry, it's a nickname. We have to go.
费利西蒂打电话了
Felicity called about the thing.
关于口腔问题
The dental problem.
好的  好  抱歉
Yes, yeah, sorry.
我们  我们的朋友
Our-- our friend has, this,
牙齿有点问题
tooth issue.
做得很好
Good work.
沃夫曼
生物制剂公司
就位
Onsite.
可以进去了
We're clear for entry.
好了  费利西蒂  接下来怎么做
All right, Felicity, what's next?
我们需要一份化学制品的样本
We need a sample of the chemical.
通过它  雷可以整理出DNA标记
With it, Ray can unscramble the DNA markers
然后我们就有机会确认出某些幽灵的身份了
and we can have a shot at IDing some of our ghosts.
去哪才能找得到
Where do we find this thing?
根据他们最近被黑的电脑显示
According to their recently hacked computers,
位置追踪
在二楼  西北角
second floor, northwest corner.
是种黄色的液体
It's a yellow liquid.
有人来了
Incoming.
四个幽灵  北面的入口
Four ghosts, north entrance.
交给我
I'm on it.
费莉西蒂  我们进来了
Felicity, we're in.
正在找那种化合物
Looking for the compound.
找到了
Got it.
绿箭侠和快手需要援助
Green Arrow and Speedy need assistance.
谢了
Thanks!
你该走了  离开这里
You should go, get out of here.
那你呢
And what about you?
我能行  走吧
I've got this. Go.
费利西蒂  我要确认一下
Felicity, I'm going for an ID
开枪射我们的幽灵的身份  准备好
on the ghost that shot at us. Stand by.
安迪
Andy?
看来死亡也不是永久的了
Well, even death's not permanent anymore.
抱歉
Sorry.
没事  没关系
No, no, it's OK.
现在什么都乱了
Nothing seems to make sense anymore.
安迪
Andy.
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe this.
很显然蜂巢伪造了他的死亡
It's obvious that HIVE faked his death.
可能这是他们招募的形式...
Maybe it was part of his recruitment..
你看了那些文件
You saw the file.
你看到了他以前是什么样  现在是什么样
You saw what kind of man my brother was, what kind of man he is.
我们还什么都不了解
We don't know anything,
除非是亲耳听安迪说出来
Not until we hear it directly from Andy.
怎样才能让他说呢
And how are we supposed to do that?
把他从蜂巢里救出来
We get him out of HIVE.
奥利弗  你怎么还能认为他是清白的呢
Oliver, how are you still giving him the benefit of the doubt?
因为他是你的家人
Because he's your family.
你说过他是个好人
You said he was a good man.
-可能他仍然是  -我不知道
- Maybe a part of him still is. - I don't know.
我知道  上个月在木场
I do. Last month at the lumber yard,
一个幽灵原本可以杀死你  但是他没有
a ghost had a chance to kill you, but didn't.
那次很奇怪
I remember thinking how weird that was,
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
除非那个幽灵就是安迪
unless that ghost was Andy.
怎么  难道他饶了我一命
So, what, he had a chance to kill me and he didn't,
我就可以不在乎他是个杀手了吗
so I'm just supposed to forget he's a killer?
不  可是你应该记住他是你哥哥
No, but you should still remember he's your brother.
我做不到  西娅
I can't square that circle, Thea.
那个蜂巢的成员跟我哥哥一点关系都没有
That HIVE member was nothing like my brother.
我哥哥已经死了
The man that was my brother's dead.
他死了
He's dead.
什么哥哥
What brother?
那个偷了毒品的犯人的哥哥
The brother of the prisoner that stole the drugs.
但全是他指使的
But only because he put him up to it.
你疯了吧
You're crazy!
那个犯人袭击你是因为你杀了他妹妹
That prisoner attacked you 'cause what you did to his sister--
你在说谎
That's a lie!
这比说我故意让他去
It's a hell of a lot more believable
袭击你可信多了
than me putting him up to attacking you.
自从你发现了那个设备后
You know what, you have had it in for me
你就一直跟我过不去
ever since you found that knap--
够了  我有办法能
Enough! I have a means of
占卜出真相
divining the truth.
你为什么杀了那个犯人
Why did you kill that prisoner?
因为他袭击了我
Because he attacked me.
拜托
Come on, man,
别在这里搞些玄乎的东西
this isn't the place for your hocus pocus crap!
你有没有让那个犯人袭击奎恩先生
Did you have that prisoner attack Mr. Queen?
当然没有
Hell no.
你在骗人
You're lying.
根据是什么  一堆树枝吗
According to what, a bunch of twigs?
瑞特  别这样  你得听我解释
Reiter, don't do this! You got to hear me out!
是他  他才是有问题的
It's him! He's the problem.
他才是有问题的
He's the problem!
你要怎么处理他
What are you going to do to him?
不处理  我认为做错的人应该改正
Nothing. I believe the wrong should make things right.
你想要见我吗
So, you wanted to see me.
这么礼貌  有点不正常啊
So polite. That's a bit atypical.
被训斥了很多次之后  我知道该听谁的话了
A guy gets slapped down enough times, he learns who's boss.
显然没有
Apparently not.
不好意思  你说什么
I'm sorry, what are you talking about?
上周我们见面后  我不幸遇到了
After our meeting last week, I had an unpleasant encounter
绿箭侠和他的同伙
with the Green Arrow and his compatriots.
我的安保人员认为
My security personnel are under the opinion
你叫我去会面
that you called that meeting so as
是为了创造机会好让他们跟踪我
to create an opportunity to have me followed.
这么说你的安保人员不相信我  那你呢
So your security guys don't trust me, but what about you?
信任就像兰花
Trust is an orchid--
很美但也很脆弱
beautiful but delicate.
需要很理想的条件才能茁壮成长
Requiring ideal conditions in order to thrive.
没有这样的条件
Without those conditions,
它就会死
it dies.
小心行事  昆汀
Tread carefully, Quentin.
信不信由你  我对你最可怕的威胁
Believe it or not, the death of your daughter
绝不只是杀死你女儿
is not the most terrible thing that I can threaten you with.
星城码头
第52滑道
马尔科姆来电
我不想跟你说话
I don't want to talk to you.
那你为什么还要接电话
Then why are you answering the phone?
因为  我
because, I...
我之前想告诉你我会过来
I would have told you I was stopping by,
可是你一直不接我电话
but you weren't taking my calls.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
帮你
To help you.
你在南达尔巴特杀死的那些人
Those men you killed in Nanda Parbat,
你应该又有杀人的欲望了吧
the effects of those deaths must be wearing off by now.
我很好
I'm fine.
嗜血的欲望又出现了  对吧
The blood lust has returned, hasn't it?
我能控制住
I have it under control.
你控制不了  西娅
You can't control it, Thea.
劳伦斯·坦纳
法务报告
劳伦斯·坦纳是谁
Who's Lawrence Tanner?
恋童癖者  被指控了多次
Pedophile. Multiple accusations,
孩子失踪
拉里·史多利
但罪名都不成立
no convictions.
当地人被指控剥削儿童
住在三个街区外
Lives three blocks down.
这个世界少一个恋童癖者会更好
The world needs one less pedophile.
这样你也能至少一个月不再想杀人了
And you need at least a month of peace.
我要出去一下  好吗
Look, I'm going to go out, OK?
等我回来的时候  你最好已经走了
And when I come home, you better not still be here,
否则我就叫警察来
or I am calling the police.
艾利克斯雇了一队保镖  你今天可以休息了
Alex hired a security detail, if you want to sit this one out.
好的  我去吧台
Yeah, I'm going to be at the bar.
其实  现在这样
Well, this is actually a better way
比你平时的夜生活好多了
than how you usually spend your evenings--
穿着皮衣去收拾别人
Dressing in leather and tying people up.
他在这呢
There he is!
他们都在等你上台发言呢
They're waiting for you on the dais.
你准备好了吗
You ready for this?
马上见分晓
About to find out.
星城警局
晚上好
Evening.
很荣幸  今晚我们共聚于此
It is our great privilege to be here tonight
向星城警局致敬
to honor the Star City Police Department.
这些男人和女人
These are a group of men and women
每天不顾生命危险保护我们
who risk their lives for us on a daily basis.
警察是个艰苦的职业
Never been an easy job,
尤其是如今  在这座城市做警察
and it has certainly never been more difficult
更是史无前例的艰难
than it is right now in our city.
这群人保卫我们的社区
These are the people that keep our streets safe,
看护我们
who watch over us.
他们在保护我们
They protect us.
对此  我十分感激
For that, I'm grateful.
星城的所有人都十分感激
And so is the rest of Star City.
我们支持你们
不错啊  虽然跟绿箭侠说的比起来
Not bad. Not quite as powerful
稍逊一筹  不过挺不错了
as the Green Arrow's, but not bad.
是吗  或许我该让他来支持我
Yeah? Maybe I should get him to endorse me.
我需要你帮我个忙
I need a favor from you.
帮我查达克手下一个杀手的位置
Need a location of one of Darhk's foot soldiers.
可能有点困难
Could be a little difficult.
达克今早叫我去他办公室
Darhk called me into his office this morning
谈了谈  说他再也不信我了
for a little chat about how he doesn't trust me anymore.
等等  你有危险吗
Wait, wait, wait, are you in danger?
但愿没有  但是
I hope not. But listen,
我在他那的时候  看到他桌上有个东西
when I was there, I saw something on his desk.
写着码头的第52滑道
Something about Slip 52 down at the docks.
如果幽灵在那里
Now, if the ghosts are there,
或许你要找的人也在那
maybe the one you're looking for will be there, too.
-好的  谢谢  -没事
- OK. Thank you. - All right.
亲爱的  你好
Hey, honey. How are you?
给
Here you go.
苏打水
Club soda.
是啊  没办法
Yeah, it has to be.
候选人的保镖可不能醉醺醺的
Can't have the candidate's bodyguard getting hammered.
你想谈谈吗
Do you want to talk about it?
兄弟姐妹复活
Resurrected siblings
这事我已经驾轻就熟了
are kind of in my wheelhouse.
这不太一样  劳蕾尔
It's not quite the same thing, Laurel.
莎拉不是...
Sara wasn't really...
杀手组织的成员
a member of an organization of killers?
我知道  现在你的脑子里
I'm sure there are a million things
有万千思绪  我只是想说
going through your head right now. All I'm saying is,
对于你哥哥还活着这件事
make one of them an appreciation for the fact
起码要有一丝欣慰
that your brother is actually alive.
为什么呢  这样我就能...
Well, why, so I can...
继续幻想着
hold off some kind of false hope
或许他是个好人吗  他不配
that he might be decent? He doesn't deserve that.
他是不配  但你配
No, he probably doesn't, but you do.
安迪死后  你的一部分也死了
After Andy died, a part of you died, too.
现在就是你痊愈的机会
And now, now is your chance to heal.
我要怎么才能痊愈
How am I supposed to do that?
当我要看着...
When I had to look...
我外甥的眼睛
my nephew in the eye
告诉他...
and tell him that...
他再也见不到自己爸爸了
he was never going to see his daddy again.
安迪死后一个月  是我人生中最灰暗的日子
The months after Andy died were the darkest times of my life.
我愿意付出一切
I would have given anything,
让安迪回来
anything to get Andy back.
我愿意付出生命
I would have sacrificed my life
让安迪和他的妻儿团圆
to have him back with his wife and his son.
我甚至愿意用自己的命来换
I would have traded my life for a stranger.
巅峰舞厅
奎恩先生  见到你很高兴
Mr. Queen, it's so nice to meet you.
谢谢
Thank you!
你认为你能为星城警局筹到更多资金吗
Do you think you can get more funding for the SCPD?
这绝对是我的首要任务
Well, that's certainly a top priority.
-真是好消息  谢谢  -应该的
- That's great news, thank you. ?- Sure.
奎恩先生  我是你的超级粉丝
Mr. Queen. Huge fan.
谢谢  你是
Thank you. Mr.?
达克
Darhk.
对于如何帮助你竞选  我有些想法
I have some ideas of how I might contribute to your campaign.
-你有空吗  -当然
- Do you have a minute? - Of course.
不止是关于财政支持
Well, it's not just about financial support.
我在商界也有很硬的关系
I have strong relations in the business circles,
在媒体界也有
media outlets as well.
这很好  但是我没有竞争对手
That's all well and good, but I am running unopposed.
所以我不明白  我为什么还需要你帮我赢呢
So I don't totally understand how you can help me win.
不是关于赢得选举
Oh, it's not about winning.
而是关于我们合作能实现的大业
It's about how much we can accomplish if we worked together.
这样啊
Right.
我不想让你难堪
And not to be indelicate,
但是你父母不再掌权之后
but a lot has changed in Star City
星城改变了很多
since your parents held sway here.
权力制衡机制也改变了
The levers of power have changed.
杰西卡·丹福斯就因为不明白这一点才会失败
And not understanding that is what doomed Jessica Danforth's bid.
你想要什么  达克先生
What do you want, Mr. Darhk?
我看过你新项目的新闻稿
I read the press release about your new project.
斯特林湾的重建项目
The restoration of Starling Bay.
重新考虑一下吧  别去动那块地
Reconsider your plans. Leave the bay as it is.
如果我拒绝呢
What if I refuse?
那么你就会有竞争对手了
Oh, well, then you'll no longer be unopposed.
奎恩先生
Mr. Queen.
达克先生
Mr. Darhk.
上山找拉斯决斗
Leaving to fight Ra's on the mountaintop,
去刺客联盟当卧底
going undercover ?with the League of Assassins,
跟女杀手约会
dating the huntress...
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在列举过去三年里
I am just listing all of the terrible ideas
你做过的所有糟糕透顶的主意
you've had over the past three years,
跟达米恩·达克合作绝对是最糟的了
of which throwing in with Damien Darhk has got to be the worst.
我不是跟达米恩·达克合作
I am not throwing in with Damien Darhk!
我是在利用他接近蜂巢
I am using him to get at HIVE.
兰斯不是已经打入内部了吗
Isn't Lance already our man on the inside?
达克不信任兰斯了
Lance has lost Darhk's trust,
所以只有这一条路...
making this the only way...
害死你自己
To get yourself killed.
还记得上一次
You remember the last time
你打算从内部瓦解一个邪恶组织吗
you tried to take down an evil organization from the inside?
-这次不一样  -为什么
- This is different. ?- Why?
-因为这次是以奥利弗·奎恩的身份  -对
- Because you'd be doing it as Oliver Queen? ?- Yep.
那市长竞选呢
What about your mayoral campaign?
你不能一边做着市长候选人
You cannot be an effective candidate for mayor
一边做着达克身边的卧底
and Darhk's undercover stooge.
扳倒达克更重要
Taking down Darhk is more important,
尤其现在我们已经知道安迪在他麾下了
especially now that we know he has Andy under his thumb.
首先  关于安迪
First, there is a whole long list of things
我们有好多不了解的地方
that we don't know about Andy.
其次  你竞选市长不是为了扳倒达克
Second, you didn't decide to run for mayor to take down Darhk.
而是为了给城市一些
You did it to give the city something that the Green Arrow
绿箭侠给不了的东西
can't give them...
希望  鼓舞
Hope. Inspiration.
别忘了这点
Don't lose sight of that.
即使是为了约翰
Not even for John.
他背叛了我们
This man betrayed us.
他把一个无辜的人
He sent an innocent man,
一个有能力的人送进了坟墓
a useful man to his grave.
他密谋反对我  你们
He conspired against me, you,
以及所有的兄弟
all of his brothers.
巴伦  拜托
Baron, please...
我是不会惩罚他的
His punishment won't come from me,
而是由他试图伤害的人来进行
but from the one he sought to hurt.
奥利弗  求你
Oliver, please.
别这样
Don't do this.
我求你了
I'm begging you.
别这样  奎恩
Come on, Queen.
求你了  对不起  对一切事情
Please. Look, I'm sorry, I'm sorry for everything!
求你别这样
Please don't do this!
用力
Harder!
我没听明白
So-- so, I'm sorry,
八年后  你的朋友和他哥哥重逢了吗
your friend was reunited with his brother after eight years?
很离谱  对吧
It's crazy, right?
是很离谱
Yeah, crazy.
你没有把你的皇冠给他吗
So you have you given him your crown yet?
他打破了你五年来一直认为
I mean, you held the record with five years
奥利弗已死的记录  所以
thinking Oliver was dead, so.
我无法想象那对你来说多艰难  西娅
I can't imagine how tough it must have been for you, Thea.
抱歉
Sorry.
我得接这个电话
You know, I should probably take this.
好
OK.
我是艾利克斯  抱歉
This is Alex. Sorry.
什么事
Yeah, what's up?
你好
Hi there.
在喝什么呢  我再请你喝一杯吧
What are you drinking? Maybe I can buy you another.
和我约会的人会不高兴的
I don't think my date would like that very much.
他又不在这
Well, I don't see him here.
你看起来是那种喜欢说反话的女孩子
You look like the kind of girl where no means yes.
来吧  宝贝
Come on, baby.
西娅  住手
Thea! Stop!
你在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
打不了吗
Can't do it?
我无法相信安迪回来了
I can't believe that Andy's back.
我该怎么向卡莉解释
How am I supposed to tell Carly?
她有权知道  约翰尼
She has a right to know, Johnny.
她最好不知道他还活着
She's better off thinking he's dead.
我觉得这不是你该做的决定
I'm not sure that's your call to make.
我什么也不确定
I'm not sure about anything.
当我第一次知道闪电侠
You know, when I first found out about the Flash,
复活泉水  以及它对西娅造成的影响时
and the Lazarus Pit and what it did for Thea...
我开始幻想安迪回来了
I began to daydream about Andy being back.
我只是会想想而已
I would just play with that idea.
我哥哥回来了
My brother's back.
我从未想过这真的会发生
I never thought it would actually happen.
我明白
I know.
我去开门
I'll get it.
-莱拉  -奥利弗
- Hi, Lyla.  - Hi, Oliver.
我能进来吗
May I come in?
当然
Sure.
我让你们俩单独聊
I'll give you two a minute.
你怎么样
How you holding up?
已经算是挺好的了  是吧
I guess as good as can be expected, right?
没有什么事能拿来作比较
Nothing really to compare this to.
至少这周没有
At least not this week.
兰斯有情报给我们
Lance has some intel for us.
码头的第52滑道
Slip 52 at the docks.
费利西蒂查过了  那个区域
Felicity checked it out, and that whole area's
整个晚上都处于关闭状态
been shut down for the entire night.
你认为那些幽灵在那有什么计划吗
Think the ghosts have something planned there?
也许你哥哥也会在
And maybe your brother.
每次我们面对那些幽灵
Every time we face the ghosts,
都是拿命在赌  我不能要你们为安迪冒险
it's Russian Roulette. I'm not risking any of you for Andy.
不是你要求  我们主动提出
You're not. We're offering.
好吧  但是就我们俩
OK. But just us.
西娅和劳蕾尔不能插手这事
Thea and Laurel sit this one out.
好
OK.
先生们  你们都来自不同的行业
Gentlemen, you all come here from different walks,
不同的生活方式
different paths.
但是全都了解一件事
But all burdened with the same knowledge--
这个世界病入膏肓
that this world is diseased.
幸运的是  我们有治疗这场瘟疫的解药
Fortunately, there is a cure for this pestilence.
先生们  这个解药
That cure, gentlemen,
就是蜂巢
is HIVE.
你们吞下的这些黄色小药片
Those little yellow pills you swallowed,
它们有一些有趣的功效
they do a few interesting things--
包括让你们合作
including making you cooperative.
我明白你们都是自愿的  这太好了
Now, I understand you all volunteered and that's just swell.
但是我认为我们都会同意任何的指挥系统
But I think we can all agree that in any chain of command,
反抗肯定是会有的
there can never be too much compliance.
我们试验一下吧
Perhaps a demonstration.
跪下
Kneel.
这座城市的人们
The people of this city--
虽然也没剩多少人了
what's left of them, at any rate--
他们称你们为幽灵
they call you ghosts.
而他们不知道自己有多么正确
And they have no idea how right they are.
上面
Up there!
杀了那个穿绿衣服的
Kill the green one.
这不能怪你  约翰  是我的决定
This isn't on you, John, it was my call.
我就不该让你做这决定
I never should have let you make it.
费利西蒂  能让我们单独聊聊吗
Felicity, can you give us a second?
不  我认为我该留下来
No, I think I should stay.
我刚想起来
I just remembered,
我有什么东西要弄
I got that thing in the whatever with the what's-it.
奥利弗  算了吧
Oliver, let this go, man.
我已经放弃了
I have.
你差点害死自己
You almost got yourself killed.
我还遇到过更危险的情况
I've been a lot closer to almost killed.
-安迪做了他的选择  -这点你并不知道
- Andy made his choice. - You don't know that.
约翰  你看到今晚发生的事
John, you saw what was going on tonight.
那些人受到了某种药物的影响
Those men, they were under the influence of something.
打乱他们DNA的那种药物
Whatever pill is scrambling their DNA
让他们很容易受到邪恶暗示的影响
is also making them susceptible to dark suggestion.
好吧  你看不清你的家人
All right, just because you have a blind spot for your family,
别指望我也会这样
don't expect me to, as well.
我想说的重点不是这个
That-- that's not what this is about.
不是才怪
The hell it's not.
家人就是重点
Family is exactly what this is about.
不管是不是罪犯
Criminal or not.
不管有没有受到影响
Under the influence or not.
八年来  安迪让他的儿子和妻子相信
Andy let his son and his wife believe he was dead
他已经死了  奥利弗
for eight years, Oliver.
八年啊
Eight years!
这没有任何借口
And there's no excuse for that.
-没有  -约翰  我只是  你不知道
- None. - John, I'm just... you don't know.
奥利弗  是你不知道
Oliver, you don't know.
你有那种令人费解的方式
You have this inexplicable way
来为一切找借口  只因为是家人
of excusing everything just because it's family.
一点也不令人费解  我是让你...
It's not inexplicable! I'm asking you...
我是让你对安迪抱有希望
I'm asking you to hold out hope for Andy,
因为我需要那种希望
because I need that hope.
我需要相信
I need to believe
无论我们生活中发生了什么事
that no matter what happens in our lives,
无论我们受到多少黑暗的影响
no matter how much darkness infects us,
我需要相信我们都能从黑暗中回来
I need to believe that we can come back from that!
正是这种想法
And it was exactly that
去年指引着你走向刺客联盟
thinking that led you to the League last year.
看来你没从中吸取教训
Doesn't seem like you learned much from that.
费利西蒂告诉你了
Felicity told you?
与达克合作  奥利弗
Getting in bed with Darhk, Oliver?
我不明白你怎么能考虑这种事
I don't see how you can even consider it.
我们会打倒这个人的
We are going to take this guy down,
无论用什么办法
and no idea is off the table.
我以为你会换一种方式  奥利弗
I thought you're doing things differently, Oliver.
从内部打击达克
Fighting Darhk from the inside
就是从阴暗处打击达克
is just fighting Darhk in the shadows.
你想用不同的方式吗  你想要办法吗  好
You want to do things differently? You want ideas, fine.
那我们就光明正大地打倒这个混蛋
Let's take this son of a bitch down in the light of day.
时间刚好
Just in time.
什么刚好
For what?
烤蜥蜴
Ah, roasted lizard
加一点芫荽和海盐
with a little bit of coriander and sea salt.
我用尖利的石子剥皮的技术越来越好了
I've gotten better at removing the skin with a sharp rock.
我吃过了
I ate already.
谢谢
Thank you.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
今天过得挺不顺的
It's a hard day.
泰安娜...
Taiana...
我得...
I have to...
我得告诉你一些你哥哥的事
I have to tell you something about your brother.
瓦勒德
Vlad?
他没事吧
Is he all right?
不
No.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
什么意思
What do you mean?
-他...  -泰安娜
- Is he-- - Taiana...
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.
不好意思  我让柯蒂斯拿了些工具过来
Sorry, I had Curtis grab some more toys
这样我就能继续研究你的牙齿
so I could keep working on your tooth.
没关系  反正今晚应该也不会
That's ok; I don't think we're going to be using the table
在这张桌子上吃饭
for eating tonight, anyway.
奥利弗和约翰正忙着对付
Oliver and John are busy fighting over
约翰那个原来并没死的哥哥
John's not-so-dead after all brother.
我应该问一问吗
Do I even want to ask?
这样说吧  现在不是只有你一个人
Let's just say you no longer corner the market
没有像人们以为的那样死透了
on not being dead as people think.
不过约翰的弟弟
Though, in John's brother's case,
倒是有个很好的理由
he does have a pretty good excuse--
不像某些人
Unlike some people.
你见过别人了吗
Have you seen anyone?
当然没有  我忙着研究你的牙齿呢
Of course not; I've been busy here working on your tooth.
你在拖时间  雷  你起死回生后
You're stalling. Ray, when you come back from the dead,
应该重新回到正轨
you're supposed to start living again.
怎么了
What's going on?
我一直在回顾过去六个月发生的事
I've been catching up on the past six months.
我的公司  我的城市  我的生命
My company, my city, my life.
感觉就像汤姆·索亚在看自己的葬礼
And I feel like Tom Sawyer watching his own funeral.
只不过没人在意我罢了
Except in my case, nobody really cares.
不是这样的  雷
That is not true, Ray.
给星城改名的确很不错
Renaming Starling Star City is nice,
但瞧瞧这地方发生了什么事
but then take a look to what's happened to the place.
而我所创建的公司
And my company, this thing I've built
应该比我活得更久
that was supposed to outlast me,
现在却苟延残喘
is now on life support.
因为它需要你
Because it needs you.
做什么呢
To do what?
做跟我死前一样的事吗
The same thing I was doing before I died?
现在那样一点用都没有
Obviously that didn't amount to anything.
这种自怨自艾的情绪不适合你
Oh, self-pity is not a good look on you.
我觉得这不是自怨自艾
Ah, I don't think it's self-pity.
我觉得这是自我反思
I think it's self-reflection.
如果我要回到正轨
If I'm going to come back to life,
我就应该弄明白我生存的意义是什么
I have to figure out what it is that I'm living for.
好吧
Ok.
我研究了你给我的臼齿
I played around with your bicuspid a bit.
那些化合物已经破坏了
Ah, the, uh, compound definitely broke down
牙齿上残存的DNA
the residual DNA on the tooth.
其实这种做法还挺别出心裁的
It's pretty inventive, actually.
有没有办法重建DNA
Is there any way to reconstitute the DNA
让我们能够查出他们的身份
so we have a shot at iding these guys?
不行  等位基因一旦分解
No. Once the alleles are decomposed,
就永远消失了
they're gone for good. Yeah.
既然这个方法行不通
So since that was a dead end,
我就重新研究了一下
I took another look at the polymer
用于制造假牙的聚合物
the fake tooth was made of.
我发现有氟化钠的痕迹
Uh, I found faint traces of sodium fluoride.
就像水中残留的吗
Like from water?
那种浓度不可能
There's no way that the concentration
高到可以留下任何残余
could be high enough to leave behind any sort of residue.
如果在饮用水中的氟化钠含量
It would if there was an unusually
本来就超出常量就很有可能
high Sodium fluoride count in the drinking water,
比如因为这个原因
like say in the facility that was closed down
而关闭的地方
for that very reason.
穆勒精神病治疗中心
Muller Psychiatric Center.
不得不承认这的确很讽刺
You got to admire the irony
达米恩·达克把他的坏人大军
of Damien Darhk keeping his army of bad guys
藏在废弃的疯人院里
in a defunct looney bin.
作为一个觉得自己毫无意义的人  你做得真不错
Not bad for a guy who thinks his life didn't add up to anything.
我才不要一直那样
Never going to outlive that one.
大家都清楚我们的计划了吗
Everyone clear on the plan?
我之前听了百八十遍也不明白
You know, I wasn't the first 80 times we went over it,
现在我觉得我知道了
but now I think I got it.
怎么了  伙计们
What's going on, guys?
费利西蒂查到了
Felicity found a probable location
幽灵基地的可能所在地
for the Ghosts' base of operations.
那些家伙可不好对付
These guys are not going to be easy to take out.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我们没有打算端掉幽灵
We're not trying to take down the Ghosts;
没有这个人力
we don't have the manpower.
我们要找安迪
Going after Andy.
奥利弗为了帮安迪差点搭上了性命
Guys, Oliver nearly got himself killed trying to help Andy.
我不会让你们重蹈覆辙
I'm not letting you do the same.
对不起  但这不由你来决定
I'm sorry, but it's not really just up to you.
我曾经尽全力
I did everything that I could
把我的妹妹带回来
to bring my sister back,
我觉得你哥哥也值得你这样做
and I think your brother deserves the same.
不  劳蕾尔
No, Laurel,
这样说吧...我并不这么觉得
that's just it-- I don't think he does.
我不知道奥利弗跟你们说了什么...
And I don't know what Oliver told you--
他告诉了他们最重要的两件事
He told them the only two things that matter--
安迪被达克影响了
Andy's under Darhk's influence,
以及我们得救他出来
and we need to get him out.
我不能让你们为一个
I can't let you risk your life
不值得你们涉险的人搭上性命
for someone who does not deserve it.
那是你的决定  但我们已经做了我们的决定
That's your call. But we've made ours.
我们走
Let's move.
我们就位了
We're onsite.
虽然是半夜三点钟  但是卫星侦测出
Oh, satellite's reading a hell of a lot of activity
很多活动信号  我猜大概有五十左右名幽灵
for 3:00 in the morning. I'm guessing 50 or so ghosts
未知数量的新人
plus who knows how many recruits.
等等  如果那些幽灵还穿着
Hey, wait, if the ghosts are wearing
那些万圣节戏服
their usual halloween costume,
那我们怎么分得清哪个是安迪
Then how are we supposed to tell which one's Andy?
这就要靠你们的新照相机了
That's what your fancy new cameras are for.
柯蒂斯的小礼物
A little gift from Curtis.
利用红外透镜可以看透幽灵朋友的面具
Infrared lenses should virtually unmask our ghosty friends.
太帅气了
Sick.
准备好了吗
Ok, ready?
我就位了
I'm in position.
就位
In position.
这不仅仅是行动基地
This isn't just a base of operations.
感觉像是一个中转站
It looks like a staging area.
-中转什么  -装备
- For what? - Equipment.
军用箱上标志为G65
Military crates marked G6:5.
有什么意义吗
Does that mean anything?
也许他们在玩宾果游戏
Maybe they're playing bingo.
还是不要这么假设了
Let's assume that's not it.
致命武器
Deadly bingo.
我们得找出安迪
We need to get an id on Andy.
到时候你们等我信号再出手
When we do, you wait for my signal before engaging.
我可能等不了了
Yeah, I might not have that option.
快手
Speedy?
她被发现了  三楼  大楼西南方
She's been spotted, third floor, southwest building.
我也被发现了
I've been spotted, too.
我可能看见我们的目标了
I might be able to get a visual on our target!
正在等待确认
Waiting on confirmation.
狄格尔·安德鲁
就是他  你抓住他了  就是你右边那个
That's him, you got him, the one on your right.
实际上  是他抓住我了
Actually, he's got me!
我搞定他了
I got him.
但他看上去挺沉的  我需要人搭把手
He looks pretty heavy, though. So I could use a hand.
我这就过去
I'm on my way.
小玛瑞达[《勇敢传说》女主角]
It's Merida.
你是不是早该上床睡觉了
Aren't you out a little bit past your bedtime?
你的格斗风格让我看出了一点东西
I've seen something of your fighting style.
你是被拉斯·厄尔·高福训练出来的
You were trained by Ra's Al Ghul.
告诉我  马尔科姆最近如何
Tell me-- how is Malcolm doing these days?
这招一般都有用啊
That usually works.
黑金丝雀找到安迪了
Black Canary's got Andy,
但她需要人帮忙才能到出口
but she needs help reaching the exfil.
这边我来搞定
I got this!
-你确定吗  -快去
- Are you sure? - ?Go!
你能来  真好
It's nice of you to show up.
我兄弟需要我
My brother needed me.
穿绿衣服的那个
The green one.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you,
谢谢  谢谢大家
thank you, all of you.
帕尔默  就连对你我也要说声谢谢
Palmer, even you, thank you.
荣幸之极  做点有用的事感觉挺好的
My pleasure. Feels good to do something useful.
我已经消沉了好一阵子了
It's been a while.
那是不是意味着我可以期待明天上班时见到你
Does that mean I can expect to see you at work tomorrow?
不是
No.
不能一直重复做那些没用的事情了
Can't keep doing the same useless, ineffective things. You know?
我得做些不一样的事
I got to do something different.
我要花一段时间弄清楚到底该做些什么
I'm going to take some time and figure out what that is.
但是  在你们需要我的时候
But, it still include
我依然会时不时接些超级英雄的活
the occasional super heroics whenever you need me.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我和我哥哥有一场迟到了很久的谈话
Well, I have a long overdue chat with my brother.
我希望你是对的
I hope you were right.
我也希望
Me, too.
-你是对的  -关于哪件事
- You were right. - About what?
达克
Darhk.
我思考了你说的话以及对付他的办法
I thought about what you said, and how to fight him.
我会光明正大地把他打败的
I'm going to do it in the light of day.
很好  你有什么计划
Good. What did you have in mind?
你会知道的
You'll see.
我们就不应该上那艘该死的船的
We never should have gotten on that damn boat!
瑞特的人劫持了我们工作的那艘游艇
Reiter's men hijacked the yacht that we were working on.
我之前是潜水教练
I was a dive instructor
而瓦勒徳是甲板水手
and Vlad was the deckhand.
他们把我们船上所有人都杀了
They killed everyone on our charter
然后把我们带到了这里
and they brought us here.
发生什么事了
What happened?
瓦勒徳怎么了
With Vlad?
康克林
Conklin.
我要杀了他  那个畜生
I'll kill him, that monster!
泰安娜  等等  等等
Taiana, wait, wait.
我要杀了他  惩罚他的所作所为
I'm going to kill him for what he did!
康克林...  很可恶
Conklin is... is terrible,
但他不是问题关键
but he's not the problem.
他只是个棋子
He's just a pawn.
什么的棋子
Pawn for what?
瑞特的计划
For Reiter's plan.
这是什么
What is this?
这是炼狱的地图
This is a map of Lian Yu,
我觉得它指向了
And I think that it leads
瑞特在寻找的东西
to whatever Reiter is looking for.
你能看得懂这图吗
Can you follow it?
没有...
Not without a...
这座岛的详细的测量图就不行
detailed survey map of the island.
我们要去哪里搞到那东西
Where would we get something like that?
我有个主意
Well, I had an idea.
虽然希望很渺茫  但是值得一试
It's a long shot, but it's worth a try.
要想达到目的  我需要你的帮助
To get there, I'll need your help.
谢谢你过来
Thank you for coming.
你确定没有叫星城警局的人
Are you sure you don't have the SCPD
在厨房里等着抓我吗
waiting for me in the kitchen?
别疑神疑鬼的
Don't be so paranoid.
我上次来时
You did threaten me with arrest
你确实威胁说要让警察抓我
the last time I popped by.
所以...
So...
你是重新考虑了我的建议吗
did you reconsider my advice?
是的
Yes.
但我依然不准备接受
And I'm still not going to take it.
听着...
Look...
我觉得我也许找到了另一种方法
I think I might have found a different way
能控制住自己嗜血的欲望
for me to control my blood lust,
一个不需要杀人的办法
one that does not include killing people.
那需要什么
What does it include?
达米恩·达克
Damien Darhk.
昨晚  我们在追捕蜂巢
Last night, we went after HIVE,
然后我碰上了达米恩
and I ran into Damien.
我见识过他用他的能力能做些什么
I've seen what he can do with his powers,
但当他试图把那种能力用在我身上时
but when he tried to use them on me,
竟然伤害到了他自己
it completely backfired.
而且我嗜血的欲望也消失了
And my blood lust was gone.
至少会消失一阵子
I mean, at least for a little while.
所以我想要的  就是让你帮我
So what I want is for you to help me
想个办法永久摆脱这种欲望
figure out a way to make that permanent.
安迪  我都不知道该从何说起
Andy, I don't even know where to begin.
安迪  我需要弄明白
Andy, I need to understand.
你能帮我弄明白吗
Can you help me understand?
文件里写的是真的吗
Is what's in this file true?!
安迪  回答我
Andy, answer me.
机密文件
是真的
It's true.
全都是真的
All of it.
来的媒体还真多啊
Well, this is quite a lot of media
为了这个  你怎么称呼它来着
for a, what'd you call it?
-嬉皮式的琐碎项目  -没错
- Hippie-crunchy program. - That's right.
我一直很乐意承认错误的
Always happy to admit when I'm wrong.
祝你在台上好运
Good luck up there.
抱歉我来晚了
OK, sorry I'm late.
没事
You're fine.
我们才刚准备开始
We're just getting started.
那个  我...
So, I...
没有因为斗殴而被捕
haven't been arrested for battery yet.
我一直在想...
I keep thinking...
要不是我制止了你
you would have killed him
你可能就把他打死了
if I hadn't stopped you.
我那晚过得很糟糕
I just had a really bad night.
我想问问
I guess I'm just asking if...
你能不能耐心点...
maybe you could be a little patient...
对待我
with me.
团结
奎恩 竞选市长
谢谢各位的到来
Thank you all for coming.
我的
My,
我的竞选顾问
my campaign advisor
认为基于这座城市的现状
doesn't think that saving the bay is the right fight
拯救海湾并不是正确之举
given the state the city is in.
但我希望大家明白我并非看不见
But I'd like everyone to know that I'm not blind
星城的问题所在
to Star City's problems.
我今天之所以站在这里
And I wouldn't be here today
是因为我相信这个项目能解决这些问题
if I wasn't confident that this program could help solve them.
而我之所以选择这个海湾
And the reason I chose the bay
是因为它处于城市的中心地带
is because it's in the center of the city.
是露天的公开区域
It's out in the open.
人人都看得见
For everyone to see.
拯救星城的努力不应在阴暗中进行
The fight to save Star City isn't going to be fought in the shadows.
应该光明正大地进行
It's going to be fought in the light of day.
我向你们保证
And I promise you,
向所有人保证
all of you,
我永远不会停止努力拯救这座城市的
that I will never stop fighting to save this city.